<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portfolio</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2 (Modeling)</title>
      <link>/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project2/</guid>
      <description>Sandhya Srinivasa, ss64834  Question 0: Introduction (5 pts) Introduce your dataset and each of your variables (or just your main variables if you have lots) in a paragraph. What are they measuring? How many observations?  My dataset includes GDP, the governor, women’s weekly median earnings, men’s weekly median earnings, the region, and net immigration for each of the states in the US in 2018. The GDP variable (in millions of dollars) is a measure of economy for each of the states in 2018 and is essentially the gross domestic product.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1: Exploratory Analysis</title>
      <link>/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project1/</guid>
      <description>Sandhya Srinivasa, ss64834
Introduction (4 points) My two datasets include a poverty dataset and a birth and death dataset. The variables in the poverty dataset are poverty counts and percents in 2017 and 2018 by US state or territory (includes Puerto Rico, etc). The variables in the birth and death dataset are fertility rates, birth counts in 2017, death rate, and death counts in 2018 by US state or territory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Projects Here are some projects I have recently completed:
  Project 1: Exploratory Data Analysis with Tidyverse Tools
  Project 2: Modeling, Testing, and Classification
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python</title>
      <link>/blog/python/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/python/</guid>
      <description>The above image shows the structure of DNA, a double helix. DNA plays a major role in our body because we use it as a template to make RNA. This can be done through transcription and translation, and, during translation, a codon codes for each amino acid in the polypeptide. A codon is a three bases/nucleotides in DNA. This is why we will be examining k-mers.
Using R I was able to do the following:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>/resumer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resumer/</guid>
      <description>Biography My name is Sandhya Srinivasa, and I was born in India. I came to the US when I was about a year old, and have been living in Texas ever since.
 Education I attended Village High School under the IB Diploma program. After graduating highschool, I attended the University of Texas at Austin as a Biology major.
 Interests Most of my interests are centered around the outdoors.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>